Guide to the Yasser Alwan Collection 1890-1970 AD.MC.002
AbuDhabi
- Series II: Egypt, 1895-1971 (Box 1-7)
  - Wedding Portrait Series - A bride and groom holding white gloves. 22.5 x 25.8 cm, Undated; Studio Photo Georges, 23 Mousky, Cairo, (Egypt) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Arabic Writing; Brides; Cairo, Egypt; Couples; Gelatin Silver Prints; Gloves; Grooms; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Wedding Dresses; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veils
  - Wedding Portrait Series - A bride and groom posing in front of a painted backdrop of the moon. 27.3 x 18.8 cm, Undated; Venus Photo Studio, Ex Studio Hanselmann, A. Artinian, Le Caire, 44 Rue Kasr El Nil (Egypt) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Brides; Cairo, Egypt; Couples; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Grooms; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Wedding Dresses; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veils
  - Wedding Portrait Series - A bride and groom, the bride is wearing a short dress with lace detailing. 19.0 x 14.0 cm, Undated; Studio Photo Lords (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Wedding Portrait Series - A seated bride and groom, the bride wears a beaded brocade dress. 39.0 x 28.7 cm, Undated; Studio Zola, Cairo, Egypt (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Brides; Cairo, Egypt; Couples; Gelatin Silver Prints; Grooms; Photographic Prints; Shoes; Studio Photography; Wedding Dresses; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veils
  - Wedding Portrait Series - A bride seated holding an ostrich feather fan, the groom stands behind her. 34.7 x 25.8 cm, 1920; Studio Zola, Cairo, Egypt (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Arabic Writing; Brides; Cairo, Egypt; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Grooms; Hand Fans; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Wedding Dresses; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veils
  - Wedding Portrait Series - A bride and groom seated in ornate chairs surrounded by flowers. 16.5 x 22.3 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Bow Ties; Brides; Couples; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Flowers; Gelatin Silver Prints; Grooms; Handkerchief; Photographic Prints; Wedding Dresses; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veils
  - Wedding Portrait Series - A bride with a long veil seated in a chair with the groom standing behind her holding white gloves, with a painted backdrop in the background. 24.0 x 18.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Brides; Couples; Egypt; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Gloves; Grooms; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Wedding Dresses; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veils
  - Wedding Portrait Series - A bride in a lace dress with a long veil, holding flowers, with a man in a white suit jacket. 24.4 x 17.1 cm, 6 May 1953; Studio Paris, 161 Shobra Street, Cairo, Egypt (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Brides; Cairo, Egypt; Choubra / Shubra, Egypt; Couples; Gelatin Silver Prints; Grooms; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Wedding Dresses; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veils
  - Wedding Portrait Series - A bride in a long dress with a veil, the groom is wearing a dark suit and glasses. 24.5 x 17.1 cm, 1959; Studio Paris, 161 Shobra Street, Cairo, Egypt (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Brides; Cairo, Egypt; Choubra / Shubra, Egypt; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Grooms; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Wedding Dresses; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veils
  - Wedding Portrait Series - A groom in a white jacket, with the bride seated in a lace dress and long veil. Arabic text on reverse: "Souvenir from Mr Lotfi". 22.2 x 15.8 cm, 11 (?) 1952; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Arabic Writing; Bow Ties; Brides; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Grooms; Photographic Prints; Signature; Wedding Dresses; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veils
  - Wedding Portrait Series - A bride wearing a tiara, with a groom in a white jacket. 31.8 x 22.8 cm, 17 August 1950; Studio Broadway, 10 Rue Cherif Pacha, Alexandria (Egypt) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Alexandria, Egypt; Bow Ties; Brides; Gelatin Silver Prints; Grooms; Jewellery; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Wedding Dresses; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veils
  - Wedding Portrait Series - A couple posing outside in a garden, the woman wears a detailed beaded dress. 30.7 x 24.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Brides; Couples; Egypt; Evening gown / Ball gown; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Grooms; Jewellery; Men; Photographic Prints; Wedding Dresses; Wedding Portraits; Women
  - Wedding Portrait Series - A seated bride and groom, looking off camera. 33.6 x 24.5 cm, Undated; Mitry's Photo Studio, Cairo (Egypt) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Brides; Cairo, Egypt; Couples; Gelatin Silver Prints; Gloves; Grooms; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Wedding Dresses; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veils
  - Wedding Portrait Series - A groom with white gloves standing beside a bride with a bouquet. 34.2 x 28.8 cm, 134 Hijri; Studio Nasib Habib, Faggala Street No. 78, Cairo, Egypt (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Brides; Cairo, Egypt; Flowers; Gelatin Silver Prints; Gloves; Grooms; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Wedding Dresses; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veils
  - Wedding Portrait Series - A bride and groom posing on some steps with their bridesmaids and groomsmen. 24.3 x 36.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Brides; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Grooms; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Swords & Knives; Uniforms; Wedding Ceremony; Wedding Dresses; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veils; Women
  - Wedding Portrait Series - A bride and groom, the groom wears glasses and hold a pair of gloves. 38.2 x 26.4 cm, Undated; Studio Riad Chehata Photography, Egypt (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Brides; Couples; Egypt; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Gloves; Grooms; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Wedding Dresses; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veils
  - A couple, the woman wears an elaborately detailed dress and the man is wearing a three piece suit. 24.0 x 17.5 cm, Undated; Studio Rob Paul, Sharia Manakh, Cairo, Egypt (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Cairo, Egypt; Couples; Evening gown / Ball gown; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewellery; Men; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Wedding Portraits; Women
  - A group of nuns in white habits with a crucifix on a dark necklace. 19.8 x 28.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Nuns; Photographic Prints; Prayer beads; Religion; Religious Clothing; Religious Crosses; Religious Imagery; Rosary
  - A Coptic priest in intricate robes and hat, holding a small ornate cross and a staff. 17.5 x 11.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Coptic Cross; Coptic Dress; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Photographic Prints; Priests; Religion; Religious Clothing; Religious Crosses; Religious Imagery; Robes
  - A Coptic priest in black holding a cross and a bible. 17.2 x 12.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Coptic Cross; Coptic Dress; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Priests; Religion; Religious Clothing; Religious Crosses; Religious Imagery; Robes
  - A group of priests of varying ranks gathered around a man seated on a chair draped in a robe (linked ref1291). 8.0 x 13.1 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Priests; Religion; Religious Ceremony; Religious Clothing; Religious Crosses; Religious Imagery; Robes
  - A group of priests of different ranks gathered around a kneeling man in black with their hands on his head (linked ref1290). 8.2 x 13.1 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Priests; Religion; Religious Ceremony; Religious Clothing; Religious Crosses; Religious Imagery
  - A Coptic priest holding a large staff in one hand with a group surrounding him. 8.2 x 13.1 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Coptic Cross; Coptic Dress; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Priests; Religion; Religious Ceremony; Religious Clothing; Religious Crosses; Religious Imagery
  - Group Portrait - Three nuns with school girls in front of a building with wooden shutters (linked ref1294). 11.6 x 16.8 cm, 25 May 1924; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Buildings; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Group Portraits; Nuns; Photographic Prints; Religion; Religious Clothing; Schools / Education; Students
  - Group Portrait - Three seated priests with school boys in white uniforms (linked ref1293). 11.6 x 17.1 cm, 25 May 1924; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Boys; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Priests; Religion; Religious Clothing; Religious Crosses; Schools / Education; Students; Uniforms
  - Group Portrait - Two nuns with school girls in uniforms. 29.5 x 35.7 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Group Portraits; Nuns; Photographic Prints; Religion; Religious Clothing; Religious Crosses; Schools / Education; Students; Uniforms
  - Sports Group Portrait - Bristol University Training College's football team, posing outside a stone building. 32.5 x 27.1 cm, Undated; Studio A. Holborn, 25 Stokes Croft, Bristol (England) (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Athletes; Bristol, England; Buildings; Football team; Footballs; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Sports; Studio Photography; University
  - Sports Group Portrait - Tanta Secondary School football team. 24.3 x 27.1 cm, 1913-1914; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Athletes; Boys; Football team; Footballs; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Sports; Sports kit; Sports teams; Studio Photography; Tantah, Egypt
  - Sports Group Portrait - Basketball team with teachers. 28.5 x 25.5 cm, 1929; Studio Kofler, Cairo, Egypt (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Sports; Sports kit; Sports teams; Studio Photography
  - A large group of men in suits, posing in front of a fabric backdrop, in a garden (linked ref1169 and ref1299). 34.0 x 41.9 cm, Undated; Photo Gabriel, Mansourah (Egypt) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Buildings; Canes/Walking Sticks; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Mansoura, Egypt; Men; Photographic Prints; Suits
  - A group of men posing in a garden (linked ref1168 and ref1299). 37.5 x 42.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Buildings; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Mansoura, Egypt; Men; Photographic Prints; Statues; Suits
  - A group of men in suits and tarbouches with sashes with the crescent and star emblem (linked ref1168 and ref1169). 41.1 x 44.5 cm, Undated; Photo Gabriel, Mansourah (Egypt) (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Buildings; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Insignia / Emblem; Mansoura, Egypt; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
  - A group of men, some in religious clothing and others in tarbouches. 12.8 x 17.6 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Religious Clothing; Suits
  - A group of men in sashes with a crescent moon on them, in front of the Supreme Court, Cairo, Egypt. 29.5 x 34.8 cm, Circa 1923-1952; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Architecture; Buildings; Cairo, Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Insignia / Emblem; Lawyers; Men; Officials; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - A group of Freemasons wearing medals and sashes with the number 33. 28.8 x 34.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Freemasonry; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Insignia / Emblem; Medals; Men; Photographic Prints; Religious Crosses
  - A group of Freemasons wearing sahes and Masonic aprons. 22.5 x 28.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Freemasonry; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Insignia / Emblem; Medals; Men; Photographic Prints; Suits
  - Celebration of the promotion of Ahmad Bey Kamal, from the governor of Port Said to Security Directorate (linked ref1305). 28.0 x 35.4 cm, 1920; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Architecture; Buildings; Ceremonies; Eating; Events / Occasions; Flags; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Officials; Parties; Photographic Prints; Port Said, Egypt
  - Dignitaries and guests of honor from the celebration of the promotion of Ahmad Bey Kamal (linked ref1304). 28.0 x 35.4 cm, 1920; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Buildings; Eating; Egypt; Events / Occasions; Flags; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Officials; Parties; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - School Portrait - 9th class of boys, posing in a garden. 30.0 x 35.7 cm, 20 March 1934; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Boys; Egypt; French Writing; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Studio Photography
  - School Portrait - 10th class, of boys, in front of a building. 29.5 x 35.7 cm, 20 March 1933; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Boys; Buildings; Egypt; French Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students
  - School Portrait - 9th class, a group of boys and one girl under a large tree. 29.5 x 35.6 cm, 1934; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Trees
  - School Portrait - A group of men with young children, mostly boys in a workshop. 30.0 x 33.6 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Boys; Children; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Men; Photographic Prints; Students; Suits; Teachers
  - School Portrait - A children's nursery class in Rod Al Farag. Arabic text on front: "Studio Sami, member of the Art Phtographer Union in the Egyptian Kingdom. 27.0 x 27.5 cm, 1950-1951; Studio Sami (Egypt) (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Boys; Children; Choubra / Shubra, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Studio Photography
  - School Portrait - A group of school aged boys of varying ages, posing in front of a building with a few adult men. 35.9 x 41.9 cm, Undated; Cleopatra Photo-Studio, H. A. Carapatsopoulos, Bazar Mourour, No. 1, Cairo (Egypt) (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Boys; Buildings; Cairo, Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Studio Photography; Teachers
  - School Portrait - Young women of varying ages in school uniforms standing in front of a building with wooden shutters (same building from ref1321). 23.5 x 30.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Buildings; Egypt; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Uniforms
  - School Portrait - The Ibrahimiyye Secondary Geographic and Historical Society. 29.0 x 30.0 cm, 1926-1927; Studio Photo London, 26 Boulevard Abbas, Heliopolis (Cairo, Egypt); Unknown (Box 7, Folder 13)
    Arabic Writing; Associations / Cooperatives; Boys; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Studio Photography; Suits
  - School Portrait - In a girls' school, in matching uniforms. Photo London, Helipolis, Cairo, Egypt. 23.5 x 34.7 cm, Undated; Studio Photo London, 26 Boulevard Abbas, Heliopolis (Cairo, Egypt) (Box 7, Folder 13)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Heliopolis, Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Studio Photography; Teachers; Uniforms
  - School Portrait - A group of adolescent boys in suits and tarbouches, outside a large stone and brick building. 29.5 x 36.1 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 13)
    Boys; Buildings; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Suits; Teachers
  - School Portrait - Boys and girls playing musical instruments at the Amreeki Conservatory. 29.5 x 36.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 13)
    Boys; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Music; Musical Instruments; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Studio Photography
  - School Portrait - A group of boys in suits and tarbouches with five adult males, one in a galabeya and turban. 30.0 x 34.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 13)
    Boys; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Robes; Schools / Education; Students; Teachers; Traditional Dress; Turban
  - School Portrait - A group of school boys with teachers at the Pyramids. 20.8 x 24.9 cm, 1922-1923; Studio Mahmoud Riad (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Boys; Gelatin Silver Prints; Giza, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Pyramids of Giza; Schools / Education; Students; Studio Photography; Teachers
  - School Portrait - A class of young children in white uniforms with black bow ties, two children in the front row on telephones. 24.5 x 26.7 cm, March 1952; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Children; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Teachers; Telephones
  - School Portrait - Boys Scouts in uniform, with some adult leaders. 21.6 x 29.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Boy Scouts; Boys; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Teachers; Uniforms
  - School Portrait - A girls' school class, wearing black uniforms with white bows, on a carpet in front of a building with wooden shutters (same building from ref1312). 23.8 x 30.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - School Portrait - A group of actors and actresses of varying ages in costumes at the theater at a Nun's School. 23.7 x 30.5 cm, 1926; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Arabic Writing; Costumes; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Nuns; Painted Backdrops; Performance Plays; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Stage; Theater
  - School Portrait - A group of school boys in matching uniforms with hats and two men wearing tarbouches. 30.5 x 36.2 cm, Undated; House of Artistic Photography, under the governance of Maijan district, Cairo, Egypt (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Cairo, Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Men; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Studio Photography; Teachers; Uniforms
  - School Portrait - A group of boys wearing tarbouches, with six men. Arabic text on reverse: "1st year of the 5th class of the Tawfikkiyya School". 32.2 x 40.5 cm, 21 April 1931; Studio Charles, Cairo (Egypt) (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Cairo, Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Studio Photography; Teachers
  - School Portrait - Adolescent boys wearing uniforms, with trophies laid out in front of them. 31.0 x 37.0 cm, Undated; Studio Basma, San Stefano (Alexandria, Egypt) (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Boys; English Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Insignia / Emblem; Photographic Prints; San Stefano, Alexandria, Egypt; Schools / Education; Sports; Students; Teachers; Uniforms
  - School Portrait - A group of boys wearing tarbouches in front of a large building with columns and ornate railings (linked ref1331). 22.0 x 28.6 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Architecture; Boys; Buildings; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Teachers
  - School Portrait - A group of boys in front of an arched doorway with a map of South America in the background. Arabic text on reverse: "In the Nile School in 1926, William Youssef, who is the second to the mudir, second row." 18.8 x 24.6 cm, Unknown (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Maps; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Suits; Teachers
  - School Portrait - A group of young girls in uniorms at the Al Hussainiyya Primary School for Girls (Education Ministry Umramiya, in Giza). 17.1 x 24.5 cm, 1951; Studio Metwalli, 1 Gilli St., Septiyya, Cairo, Egypt (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Giza, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Studio Photography; Teachers; Uniforms
  - School Portrait - A group of school girls in white uniforms in a drawing class. 34.5 x 36.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Arabic Writing; Art; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Studio Photography; Teachers; Uniforms
  - School Portrait - A group of young boys in suits and tarbouches with three men. On the wall is a map and an image of a steam powered vehicle. 29.9 x 25.9 cm, Undated; Studio Foto du Gouvernement, Basile Iatropoulos (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Boys; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Maps; Men; Photographic Prints; Robes; Schools / Education; Students; Studio Photography; Suits; Teachers; Traditional Dress
  - School Portrait - A group of school boys with crossed arms and five men, outside a building (linked ref1326). 26.3 x 25.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Bow Ties; Boys; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Robes; Schools / Education; Students; Teachers
  - School Portrait - A group of boys and men, all wearing tarbouches. Arabic text on reverse: "Tahra Bey School 4th Year". 28.1 x 25.5 cm, 1928; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Teachers
  - School Portrait - A group of boys and nine teachers, in front of a stone building. 33.0 x 34.6 cm, May 1951; Unknown (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Buildings; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Teachers
  - School Portrait - A group of school boys, wearing tarbouches and five men. Al Najah School. 30.5 x 36.5 cm, Undated; Studio C. Zaphir, Tantah (Egypt) (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Studio Photography; Tanta, Egypt; Tantah, Egypt; Teachers
  - School Portrait - A group of boys and girls wearing sashes, with male teachers. Egyptian and British flags in background. 25.5 x 19.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Boys; Charity; Egypt; Flags; Fundraising; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Teachers
  - School Portrait - Girls in uniform with a man and woman. Writing on reverse. 26.3 x 31.1 cm, Undated; Studio d'Art ,Th. Canton, 24 Bd. Saad Saghloul, Alexandrie (Egypt); Studio Photo Canton, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Alexandria, Egypt; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Studio Photography; Teachers; Uniforms
  - School Portrait - A group portrait of eleven girls and two female teachers. 30.8 x 36.3 cm, 1938-1939; Unknown (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Arabic Writing; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Studio Photography; Teachers; Uniforms; Women
  - School Portrait - A group portrait of girls in uniform in a kitchen. 33.9 x 40.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Arabic Writing; Cooking; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Uniforms
  - Military Portrait - Men in uniforms, some of them holding swords (linked ref1350, ref1351, ref1354 and ref1418). 29.7 x 22.5 cm, 1927; Studio B. Edelstein, Mousky Street, Cairo, Egypt (Box 8, Folder 1)